><?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Channel_Interface_Dialstrings" xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2005, 2006 Collabora Limited</tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2005, 2006 Nokia Corporation</tp:copyright>
  <tp:copyright>Copyright (C) 2006 INdT</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="com.Nokia.Telepathy.Channel.Interface.Dialstrings">
    <tp:requires
        interface="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Channel.Type.StreamedMedia"/>
    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      An interface that gives a Channel the ability to send dial strings. The
      dial strings are used mainly for things like 2nd stage dialing or
      avoiding human interaction with interactive voice response systems (IVR).
      The syntax of dial string is in common with those defined in <a
      href="http://www.rfc-editor.org/rfc/rfc4967.txt">RFC4967</a>.
    </tp:docstring>

    <method name="Send">
      <arg direction="in" name="DialString" type="s" >
        <tp:docstring>Dial string.</tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="duration" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
        Desired duration of each tone in milliseconds, or 0 for implementation-specific default .
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="pause" type="u">
        <tp:docstring>
        Desired duration of pause between tones in milliseconds, or 0 for implementation-specific default .
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Sends the dial string on the channel.</p>

        <p>The channel will send the dial string using appropriate means,
        such as RFC 4733 audio events or SIP INFO payload.</p>

        <p>If the dial
        string is sent as distinct tones, each the tone will take the given
        duration or the implementation-specific default, if duration 0 is
        given. </p>
      </tp:docstring>
      <tp:possible-errors>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NetworkError" />
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.InvalidArgument">
          <tp:docstring>
            The given stream ID or dial string was invalid.
          </tp:docstring>
        </tp:error>
        <tp:error name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.Error.NotAvailable">
          <tp:docstring>
            The requested event is not available on this stream.
          </tp:docstring>
        </tp:error>
      </tp:possible-errors>
    </method>

    <method name="Cancel">
      <tp:docstring>
        Cancel sending the current dial string.
      </tp:docstring>
    </method>

    <signal name="Sending">
      <arg name="DialString" type="s" >
        <tp:docstring>Dialstring to be sent (optional).</tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>A dial string being sent on this stream. The signal is provided
        for visual feedback indicating the fact that the channel is
        currently used to send dialtones and the media input from user is
        not actually getting through the audio stream. It also serves as a cue for
        Cancel method.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>

    <signal name="Stopped">
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        <p>Sending the dial string on this stream has been stopped. The signal is
        provided for feedback indicating the fact that the channel is
        no more used to send dialtones and the media input from user can get
        get through the stream.</p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </signal>

  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
